<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Roomy</title>
    <link>https://wacilpong.github.io/blog/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Roomy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://wacilpong.github.io/blog/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Mushroomy&#39;s 1st Blockcahin Story</title>
      <link>https://wacilpong.github.io/blog/post/blockchain-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wacilpong.github.io/blog/post/blockchain-1/</guid>
      <description>Blockchain  Database 기반의 장부라고 보면 된다. 트랜잭션을 해쉬값과 함께 블록(비트코인은 대략 1MB정도의 데이터를 1블록에 담음)에 저장하고, 그 다음 블록은 이전 해쉬값과 해당 해쉬값을 같이 담아서 연결시킨다. 이것이 블록체인이다.
 참고1 blockchain demo
참고2 blockchain .com

Mining  보통 Nounce값과 데이터값을 함께 조합하여 해쉬값을 만들어낸다. 이때 0으로 시작되는 해쉬값의 nounce값을 찾는 일종의 퀴즈가 바로 &amp;lsquo;채굴&amp;rsquo;이다.  ex) 000000000000000...(중략)   난이도는 그때그때 달라진다. 많은 사람이 모여 range를 정하고 채굴하면 더 효과적일 수 있어, 마이닝풀을 통해 채굴한다.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Angular directive example</title>
      <link>https://wacilpong.github.io/blog/post/angular-directive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wacilpong.github.io/blog/post/angular-directive/</guid>
      <description>What is directive ? Use it to attach custom behavior to elements in the DOM. Basic Example  This is a simple directive to change chevron background-image as clicking the element.  (1) HTML &amp;lt;label appChevron class=&amp;quot;chevron&amp;quot; style=&amp;quot;background-image: url(&#39;/assets/images/arrow-down.svg&#39;);&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/label&amp;gt;  
(2) TS (Of course it needs to be imported to app.module.ts declarations) import { Directive, ElementRef } from &#39;@angular/core&#39;; @Directive({ selector: &#39;[appChevron]&#39; }) export class ChevronValidate { constructor(el: ElementRef) { const div = document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When we connect ssh with .pem</title>
      <link>https://wacilpong.github.io/blog/post/when-connect-ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wacilpong.github.io/blog/post/when-connect-ssh/</guid>
      <description>We sometimes need to connect to computer in other network. It is necessary the key like pem(Private Enhanced Mail) When we connect. I will just write the flow about it.

flow  Generate .pem key (I am using AWS). Change mode of .pem file to 400 to read it. Identify file and connect to ssh (AWS linux for me). DONE  

Change permission of file I will change mode of key file and connect to ssh with it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publish to aws s3 with s3cmd</title>
      <link>https://wacilpong.github.io/blog/post/aws-publish-to-s3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wacilpong.github.io/blog/post/aws-publish-to-s3/</guid>
      <description>Create S3 bucket Create S3 bucket with public access in aws S3 console, because it is just for testing. And add static website hosting property with index.html (entry point).

Create CloudFront Distributions Create in aws CloudFront console. And Just keep all settings.

Connect domain with CloudFront If you don&amp;rsquo;t have routing domain in aws Route 53 console, create it first like test.example.com. It just depends on your url rules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To configure https with AWS</title>
      <link>https://wacilpong.github.io/blog/post/set-https-with-aws/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wacilpong.github.io/blog/post/set-https-with-aws/</guid>
      <description>flow  Request a certification for SSL/TLS in ACM (AWS Certificate Manager). Create ELB (Elastic Load Balancer) from EC2 management console. Create EC2 instance, and connect to ELB. Create record set or new hosted zone, and set alias the ELB in Route53. Access SSH with the keypair that can be generated while creating EC2 instance. Now we can access public IP if we didn&amp;rsquo;t configure anything in AWS console. So, connect that IP in shell.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To set virtual python environment with mongoDB</title>
      <link>https://wacilpong.github.io/blog/post/pyvenv-with-mongodb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wacilpong.github.io/blog/post/pyvenv-with-mongodb/</guid>
      <description>Step 1. Install python and mongoDB I am using homebrew. So it can be possible to use brew command. Oh, and macOS actually has a python(2.x), but I need 3.x version so I installed it. 맥에는 파이썬 2.x 버전으로 이미 설치되어 있지만, 나는 3.x버전이 필요해서 따로 설치했다. 그리고 모든 설치는 homebrew로 했다.
brew install python3  
And install mongoDB too.
brew install mongodb  
Step 2. Run mongoDB Now we can use mongod command which is a command to run mongoDB !</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My recently junior web developer interview</title>
      <link>https://wacilpong.github.io/blog/post/my-recently-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wacilpong.github.io/blog/post/my-recently-interview/</guid>
      <description>what kind of companies? 힙한 분위기를 느끼고 싶어서 스타트업만 건드렸다. 블록체인, 핀테크, 클라우드IDE, AI 등등 다양한 분야의 회사에 신입 개발자로 지원했다. 프론트엔드/백엔드 가릴 것 없이 넣었고, 주로 nodeJs 기반의 회사로 넣었다. 12월 4일부터 12월 8일까지 일주일 간 인터뷰만 보러 다녔다.
I apply to 7 different startups that developing web like blockchain, fintech, cloud IDE, traslating AI, medical AI. The most of them are based on nodeJs. I was an interviewee during 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>